Madison Reynolds

Mesa, AZ 85201 | Phone: (480) 267-9637 Email: madison_reynolds@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/madison-reynolds-2a1669a/

GitHub: https://github.com/mradison?tab=repositories

Portfolio: https://mradison.github.io/advanced-css-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with demonstrated experience across the Software Development Lifecycle with JavaScript as the primary Object Oriented Programming Language. Certified in agile, waterfall and scrum methodologies and frameworks. Certified Enrollment Representative with over seventeen years of experience coaching and mentoring thousands of students in higher education. Recognized thought leader for improving student experience and student outcomes. Collaborator who thrives on acquiring new skills and overcoming obstacles.

SKILLS

Platforms/Programs/Tools: JavaScript (ES6), React.js, MongDB (NoSQL), Mongoose, MVC, CSS3, HTML5, GitHub, jQuery, Bootstrap, Jira, Slack, Node.js, OOP, SQL, MySQL, Bulma, Rest API, Express.js, ORM, Sequelize, Handlebars, Java, C++, .Net, Software Architecture

Concepts: Scope management; work breakdown structures; project lifecycle management; schedule management, agile methodologies; Scrum framework including the Kanban method; Object Relational Mapping, Object Oriented Programming, User Authentication, Security Session and Storage

PROJECTS

Development and launch of a mobile first website for users who want to buy a used car

https://aqueous-coast-47792-7cd474c52b1d.herokuapp.com/

Summary: The Used Car Universe project involves the development and launch of a mobile first web app that allows the user to find a used car to buy. It will eventually have the ability for users to post cars for sale.

- Role: Scrum Master/Project manager and Developer
- Tools: JavaScript, Node.js, Express.js, RESTful API, Handlebars.js, MySQL, MVC, Heroku, CSS3, HTML5, GitHub, jQuery,

Development and launch of mobile first website for users who want randomly generated recipes https://mradison.github.io/MagicMenu/

Summary: The project involves the implementation of a mobile first web application that allows users to quickly generate recipes for their weekly menu - therefore, the name MagicMenu. The project also has the added feature of randomly displayed cocktail drinks to pair with the menu.

- Role: Scrum Master/Project manager and Developer
- Tools: JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, GitHub, jQuery, Bulma

Development and launch of a mobile first website for users who want to know the weather for multiple cities

https://mradison.github.io/Server-Side-API-Weather-App/

- Summary: The project involves the development and launch of a mobile first web app that allows
 the user to find the weather for multiple cities and to see the 5 day forecast for those cities as
 well
- Role: Developer

Tools: JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, GitHub, jQuery, Bootstrap

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Enrollment Representative University of Phoenix

2006-Present Phoenix, AZ

Provided students with a world class experience by using the Coaching to Decision method to cover degree program information, options, and applicable university policies pertaining to enrollment. *Key Accomplishments:*

- Coached and mentored new team members as a Team Lead (Assistant Manager Role) to become third-ranked team in enrollments for the company; maintained this ranking for three years straight.
- Improved student satisfaction by 10% through evaluation of current methods and then collaborating with senior leadership to develop the enrollment contact strategy.
- Retained students at 10% above the national average with the Reasons to Join Strategy to keep students engaged and in attendance throughout their entire education journey.

Training Manager United Parcel Service (UPS)

2004-2006

Tempe, AZ

Over three years of experience training and coaching staff as a Certified Training Manager for UPS. Trained and managed over 100 employees on how to effectively move packages in compliance with company regulatory and policy guidelines.

Kev Accomplishments:

- Led the Tempe hub from a 50% satisfaction rate to over 75% through effective management style, collaboration with other leaders, and interpersonal communication skills.
- Developed over 100 employees through observation/evaluation of skills and then coaching them on how to provide quality customer service leading to 10% increase in productivity for roughly two years.

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Developer: Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ	Expected: 2024
Certificate, Professional Scrum Master II: Scrum.org, Phoenix, AZ	2022
Certificate, Professional Scrum Master I: Scrum.org, Phoenix, AZ	2021
Certificate, Advanced Software Developerl: University of Phoenix, Phoenix, AZ	2020
Master of Business Administration: University of Phoenix, Phoenix, AZ	2008-2010
Bachelor of Science in Business: University of Phoenix, Phoenix, AZ	2005-2008